hey guys this looks like a fun one if
you want to try it on your own pause it
right now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 let's connect the radius that goes
from here through this point to here and
that's going to cut everything in half
so we will have two of these blue things
two of these white things and two of
these blue things let's call these two x
these two Y and these two Z and now we
have a way to express our Blue Area it's
going to be equal to 2x + 2 Z so now we
got to do some work to find x and z
first let's look at the entire quarter
Circle the area of a quarter circle is <
r^ 2 / 4 and the radius of this quarter
circle is equal to 4 and 4^ s means 4 *
4 and then we can cancel out these two
fours and now we know the area of this
quarter circle is equal to 4 pi and this
4 Pi is the same thing as two of these
X's plus two of the Y's plus two of the
Z's next we can divide everything by two
on the left hand side all these twos
will cancel each other out and on the
right hand side 4 Pi / 2 is the same
thing as 2 pi and then next next let's
focus on this semicircle let's color it
red and let's find the area of the red
the area of a semicircle is < R 2 / 2
this four is the diameter of the
semicircle which means the radius would
be equal to 2 and 2^ 2 is equal to 2 * 2
and these twos will cancel each other
out so the area of this red region is
equal to 2 pi and this 2 pi is the same
thing as 1X 2x + y and now we can bring
everything else back next let's cut the
semicircle in half this forward split
into 2x two and then this radius wraps
all the way around so this height is
also two now let's focus on this quarter
Circle this x piece plus the triangle
will equal the whole quarter Circle next
we can subtract triangle from both sides
these triangles will cancel each other
out on the left hand side we'll have X
and on the right hand side we'll have
quarter Circle minus triangle the
quarter Circle which is p piun r 2 / 4
the triangle which is base * height / 2
the radius of this quarter circle is
equal to 2 2^ 2 is equal to 4 and these
fours will cancel each other out so the
quarter Circle has an area of Pi and
then for the triangle the base is equal
to 2 and the height is equal to 2 these
twos would cancel each other out so the
area of this triangle is equal to 2 and
now we know that X is equal to Pi - 2 in
the place of this x we can plug in pi -
2 this 2 is going to distribute to both
of these so it becomes 2 piun - 4 next
let's subtract 2 pi from both sides and
let's add four to both sides on the left
hand side these two pies will cancel
each other out these two fours will
cancel each other out and on the right
hand side these two pies will cancel
each other out so we have y is equal to
4 now we know X and Y so we're going to
substitute that into this equation in
the place of the X we'll plug in pi - 2
and in the place of the Y we're going to
plug in four let's combine the -2 and
the four to give us 2 and then we'll do
minus Pi minus 2 from both sides on the
left hand side all of this stuff cancels
out and on the right hand side 2 pi -
piun is 1 pi and now we have Z is equal
to piun - 2 2 now that we know the
values of all three of our variables we
should be able to find the blue area the
blue area is equal to 2x + 2 Z we don't
need the Y anymore and looking at this Z
and X are both equal to Pius 2 so we can
say x is equal to Z and let's substitute
in the place of this Z and X so now we
have 2X + 2x which is equal to 4X and in
the place of the X let's plug in pi - 2
and then this four can distribute to
both of those to give us 4 Pi - 8 so we
now know that the blue area is equal to
4 piun - 8 square units that's the
answer to our question so let's put a
box around it how exciting